[Music]
the lake outside my my house has begun
to freeze over and I'm starting to brace
myself every time I open the door of my
Cottage and the biting wind pushes
through consequently it was time to
stock up my pantry and pick out some new
teas to use over the winter I remember
reading the line from Emerson there is a
great deal of poetry and fine sentiment
in a cup of tea and I really like that
saying I think it is very true for me
brewing a cup of tea along with
breakfast is a simple and wholesome form
of self-care I begin the day with the
accomplishment of nourishing my body and
in my case small achievements like this
need to be celebrated
[Music]
one way I take care of myself in winter
is that I welcome my most comfortable
clothes particularly sweaters and my
favorite cozy skirts which are very warm
which is a necessary here dresses and I
also wear leggings in connection to my
last video one way that I've tried to
feel more comfortable in my skin has
been through finding clothes that have a
comforting texture and making sure they
fit me well with room for movement if
I'm at all self-conscious or
uncomfortable my attention is drawn
Inward and my general enjoyment of the
day is affected an important part of
improving my own mental health is to
practice seeing the world truly seeing
it instead of constantly being in my own
head more than I want
to one way I do this is by making sure I
feel comfortable it is definitely easy
to dress for others instead of ourselves
and that is one reason I began to
embrace the styles of clothes I truly
enjoy
[Music]
[Laughter]
I remember when I was a little girl my
ABA lived with us for several years I
begged her to sew me a very long
old-fashioned looking dress so that I
could wear it to school I was in love
with berri Potter at the time and I
apparently wanted to emulate a person
that had not been alive for over 70
years while I studied at home for the
most part I did take a few science
classes at a local middle school and on
my first day I wore that dress with
boots I'd found at the Salvation Army I
definitely looked a little strange and I
find it hilarious that I was willing to
walk into that school looking like I'd
stepped out of
1901 I've definitely modernized my
passion since then and I now enjoy
dresses along with jeans and leggings
and all the lovely modern clothes I own
I do however love how confident I was in
my wardrobe as a 13-year-old even if I
was not always confident in myself I
still take inspiration from her to this
day
[Music]
is
[Laughter]
[Music]
I have made a change in my life recently
that has proved quite helpful especially
in the winter when I'm indoors more and
in the quiet company of my own thoughts
and that has been to distance myself
from a constant onslaught of tragic and
negative news I tend to listen to
audiobooks now while I drive instead of
the radio and this has helped a lot of
course it's so important to stay
informed and to understand what's going
on in our world and I believe that I
also think we need to take breaks when
it is necessary and also balance
negative news with positive with only a
couple quick searches I'm able to find
so many forces for good in the world
right now which are often not being
talked about nearly as much as they
should it is a good reminder that while
we should honor our feelings associated
with tragic news we can then also spend
energy going out and sharing love and
kindness with someone and being part of
something just as worthy of being on the
news this practice this has been so
healing for me it's amazing how you
don't realize the impact media has on
you until you step away from it in order
to find a balance between consuming it
and going out into the world to be the
change you want to see
[Music]
hello everyone
I hope you're all having a wonderful day
it's been just a really great week over
here I started at the bookstore and I'm
just enjoying it so much this time of
year all the little shops in town put up
their Christmas lights and then it snows
and it's just so magical walking through
it it really feels like a Thomas cancade
painting you know like one of those
paintings of the little idilic little
towns it's really cute I just love
walking around after it snowed and all
the holiday decorations are up so I'm
really excited it's been so much fun and
working at the bookstore has made me
realize how important it was for me to
put a little more balance in my life
between home life and work life and
working in town it's it's been really
positive even though I've only just
started working there I really realized
I kind of wasn't in balance with the
amount of time I was spending at home
working and going out and being in a
different environment and interacting
with people is uh really really helpful
so I I've been really enjoying it in
last week's video I got some amazing
comments and emails and letters from all
of you explaining your own personal
Journeys with body image and disorders
and addiction and it was really
meaningful to read my fiance he put it
very well once he said that to make room
for new things in our life and good
things in our life we often have to take
out other things to make space for it
and I think in so many cases that's very
true you know for me there was a lot of
bad habits I really had to replace with
much healthier ways to spend my time and
also for me personally as a artist and
lover of stories and fairy tales and you
know all types of art for me replacing
unhealthy escapism with healthy forms of
escapism was just absolutely crucial for
my journey of health and recovery and
that is something that I still do a lot
today um for example you know creating
art getting a job in town when I felt
like I was at home and in my own head a
little bit too much really finding that
Harmony and balance definitely working
at the bookstore has really helped
because I have become even more
passionate about books in such a short
amount of time it's so exciting to talk
to people about books and get book
recommendations since it's one of my
favorite forms of healthy escapism you
know I love to just step into Another
Story Another reality for a little while
it is so you know therapeutic to do this
time of year I always for some reason
get attracted to mythy ology and folk
tales and looking into the stories of
other cultures and also my own and
especially the ancient stories that have
been passed on through generations and
that is something I've been doing
recently I have been reading some books
on Native American myths and legends
which are fascinating and also some
Polynesian myths and folk tales and it's
been uh really interesting um the book
of Polynesian stories is kind of a word
for word translation so I have sometimes
really gotten lost while reading it but
it's been really fun to just you know
look into it and get to learn about the
stories of other cultures and to see
also the similarities so many different
stories from around the world all kind
of have as well so many similarities and
a lot of the same topics that are being
examined such as what is honor what does
family how do we face our fears how can
we have courage when we're scared of the
world or we're scared of something and I
find those stories very comforting
because it makes me feel like my
ancestors who lived a thousand years ago
are still you know asking the same
questions and still experiencing the
world in a way that I can still relate
to on some levels and I just I've
absolutely loved getting back into some
old myths and legends I have a book on
stories of The Tao people from Puerto
Rico and I was reading it last night and
one of the stories was about the
chupacabra and if you are Hispanic
you've probably heard of The Legend of
the chupacabra it's very popular in some
areas it is a legendary monster and the
uh story I was reading was really really
scary so I just felt like I was such a
baby I I could it took me a long time to
sleep that night it was it was really
spooky so so if you're looking into the
old myths and legends of your people I
highly encourage you but um be careful
because they really didn't mess around
in those stories some of them can be
really really spooky so after reading
some stories from Puerto Rico I was
really motivated to revisit some of my
favorite buan recipes and I've been
having a lot of fun especially because
my mom has a really great book on
traditional WTO ran recipes that I've
been looking at some of my favorite
recipes from the
are aroso aopa e
Kito I really love Kito it's kind of
like um Puerto Rican eggnog it's made
with coconut milk it's really really
good so I thought that I would share
some of those traditional recipes during
this winter when I make them for my
family because they are delicious and
I've been really motivated recently to
try old recipes but also new recipes and
really get involved more in my cultural
traditional foods on my mother's side so
I I've been very excited about that
anyway I hope you all have a wonderful
day or night thank you again for
reaching out to me with your very
personal and kind messages
and it has been so appreciated some of
them were really really touching this
week and yeah and and I wanted to say
thank you I know I'm not always able to
respond to everyone and know that I read
them and I do appreciate them I I always
put a blurb in the description bar of my
videos but do let me know that if you
have been expecting a postcard from me
and you haven't received it please send
me an email I have my email in the
description bar because the US postal
system and just the mail system in
general in the US is just going insane
it has been going crazy all year it has
been really hard to manage and it's been
very unpredictable when things are
delivered and
I have noticed a couple postcards and
even a couple packages have been lost in
the mail this year and it's it's been
it's been a wild ride so please email me
if you're expecting something from me
and you haven't received it because I
really want to do my best to make sure
that everyone gets what they were
expecting and and that's very important
to me so so please do let me know don't
be shy you know I really I really want
to get things to you if if you are a
expecting them so I hope you have a
wonderful day or night and I will see
you next week take
care what are you doing what are you
doing what are you doing
[Music]